<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>hreikin</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://hreikin.github.io/</id><updated>2023-02-24T19:56:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>First Impressions With Software Development On Termux</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/first-impressions-with-software-development-on-termux.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-02-24T19:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-24T19:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>@hreikin</name></author><id>tag:hreikin.github.io,2023-02-24:/first-impressions-with-software-development-on-termux.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A detailed post on my first impressions with software development using Termux on Android.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have been using Termux for almost a month now and figured now would be a good time to give an overview of my experiences. This will be the 2nd post in my series on "Developing Software On Android Using Termux", I will cover my general usage and workflow as well as any errors or common pitfalls I have encountered along the way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple workflows I use when developing on my tablet which I will try to outline below. Each has its use case with Dex being my favourite and probably the best all-rounder, however, the other workflows are certainly great alternatives if your tablet doesn't provide a desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Android Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most basic workflow and works surprisingly well, I was apprehensive at first as to how useful it would be but I use this workflow quite often. I use the S-Pen and a Bluetooth keyboard most of the time in this configuration but it also works well using the touch-screen keyboard and tapping with your finger for navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In "Android Mode" the tablet can be used in either the portrait or landscape orientation, I prefer using the tablet in the portrait orientation most of the time in this mode so each app I have open is wider than it would be in split-screen with the landscape orientation. Most Android tablets come with the ability to have 2 or more apps open at the same time via split-screen or pop-up mode which is where this mode shines, this is great when learning a new framework or if you are tracking down a bug and you are constantly referring to the documentation or Stack Overflow and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mouse works well in this mode but using touch for navigation is my preferred option due to how the UI is geared towards it. Certain actions like trying to click and drag something can be problematic with the mouse depending on which app is being used and it just generally feels a little more clunky to use this way. The touch-screen keyboard works as well as you would expect it to and if you don't have an external keyboard with you is perfectly capable, however, like most people (I assume) I prefer typing on a regular keyboard if typing anything of length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dex Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this workflow the most and although Dex is only provided by Samsung most other manufacturers do offer something similar under a different name. This workflow tries to give you a desktop experience on your tablet, it works best when combined with a mouse and keyboard but can also be used via touch and the touch-screen keyboard. The touch-screen keyboard in this mode can be moved, pinned and resized and although I haven't used it much I can see the benefits it provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can open multiple windows and place or resize them as you need with open windows being displayed on a taskbar along the bottom edge of the screen, this doesn't seem like much but when compared to using the application switcher in "Android Mode" I think it helps speed things up and feels more natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another awesome feature that comes with Dex is the ability to connect an external display. This can be done via casting or with a cable with my preference being to use a cable if possible. When casting to an external display the tablet screen is replicated on the external display, I find this mode useable in a pinch but it can be laggy if the network is congested so most of the time I use an HDMI cable if possible. When using an HDMI cable the tablet will display the Android UI and the external display will use Dex. This is brilliant and helps improve the multitasking capabilities available to you with apps allowed to be opened on either screen and both UI types being available to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portrait orientation cannot be used when using Dex on the tablet but if using an external display via an HDMI cable the tablet can still use the portrait orientation while showing the Android UI. I don't tend to use it this way too often but it's nice to have the option as some apps look better this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Termux X11, Chroot &amp;amp; Proot Workflows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Android and Dex workflows above all happen within the Android UI without the need for a VNC or Xserver client and even though they are great sometimes you might need to use a Linux desktop instead. For example, if you are creating a desktop application that has a GUI then you will probably need to see how it looks while developing it, this isn't possible in Android without using Termux X11, &lt;code&gt;chroot&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;proot&lt;/code&gt; in combination with either a VNC or Xserver app on Android. If your tablet doesn't come with Dex or something similar then one of these options is the closest you will get to a real desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Termux X11 allows you to install a Linux desktop that is accessed via a VNC or Xserver client along with a huge selection of your typical Linux desktop programs and others such as &lt;code&gt;code-oss&lt;/code&gt;, the open-source version of &lt;code&gt;vscode&lt;/code&gt;. Termux runs a Linux environment within Android which is a slightly different way of doing things than using a &lt;code&gt;chroot&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;proot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to use a &lt;code&gt;chroot&lt;/code&gt; your tablet needs to be rooted, however, to use a &lt;code&gt;proot&lt;/code&gt; it does not. Both methods achieve the same thing and allow you to run an ARM-based Linux OS within Android, with the differences being in their implementation due to the different required permissions on the host machine. This could be useful if Termux doesn't currently have the packages you require and could even be some people's favoured option due to the number of packages available and their familiarity with the OS. Once again, either of these methods requires using a VNC or Xserver client to be able to access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Favourite Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I would say my preferred setup is Dex running on the tablet with a Bluetooth mouse and keyboard, it allows you to set up anywhere with minimal things to carry and no weight compared to a laptop. It also features no wires unless charging the tablet in this convenient configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't spoken about the battery life yet as I would like to use it more before I comment on it but I will say so far it has been brilliant. I regularly get a full day's worth of use out of it between charges but most of what I have done hasn't been particularly resource-heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest surprises to me so far has been how much I have used the Android UI, I initially thought it would be too clunky but the experience is far from it. Combined with apps like &lt;code&gt;termux&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;code-server&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;kiwi-browser&lt;/code&gt; it is a versatile device that really shines for things like web development. Dex is the cherry on top and provides a brilliant desktop experience with or without using things like a &lt;code&gt;chroot&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;proot&lt;/code&gt; which for some can add another layer of complexity when just starting to learn.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="mobile-dev"/><category term="dev"/><category term="mobile"/><category term="termux"/></entry><entry><title>Developing Software On Android Using Termux</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/developing-software-on-android-using-termux.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-01-26T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T10:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>@hreikin</name></author><id>tag:hreikin.github.io,2023-01-26:/developing-software-on-android-using-termux.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My initial experiences trying web and software development on Android using Termux.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using Android for software or web development hasn't always been an easy or stable experience in the past however in recent years it has come on leaps and bounds. This is the 1st post in my series on "Developing Software On Android Using Termux", I will cover the apps used and my initial thoughts and impressions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I have used my phone to do things in a pinch when I have had no other option but recently I bought myself a tablet and wanted to see how feasible it would be to use it for software or web development and how far I could push it before running into any deal-breaking issues. I have never owned a tablet but the family has so as this was a rare treat for me I decided to choose a high-end one. The tablet in question is a Samsung S8 Ultra that comes with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256 GB storage (expandable by microSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 GB of RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8-core Snapdragon SM8450&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adreno 730 GPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a 14.6-inch Super AMOLED screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an S-Pen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB-C display-out capability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dex Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the 2nd or 3rd best model they do with one being available with 16 GB of RAM but it was the best that was available that I could find for purchase and I am extremely happy with it. It cannot be considered cheap costing around £1000 but it is a high-end tablet with some great specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Termux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Termux is a terminal emulator and Linux environment application available on Android. It requires no rooting or setup. A small base system is installed automatically and additional packages are available via &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;pkg&lt;/code&gt;. It is available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/termux/termux-app" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="GitHub"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://f-droid.org/packages/com.termux/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="F-Droid"&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;. Do not install the Google Play version as it hasn't been updated in a long time due to some external issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Termux allows you to set up a Linux development machine fairly easily, I have made a few Bash scripts (Github repository available &lt;a href="https://github.com/hreikin/termux-dev-setups" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="here"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you're interested.) to simplify it even further and won't go into detail about the process but once Termux is installed then after using one of my scripts I will have access to a variety of programs such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Server and/or Code OSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XFCE desktop environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/termux-firefox-splitscreen.jpg" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="termux-firefox-splitscreen" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/termux-firefox-splitscreen.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is extremely useful as I'm sure you can tell, my installation script offers a minimal or desktop version with a few key differences. The minimal version comes with Code Server which allows you to run a locally available, open-source version of VS Code accessible from an Android or desktop browser. The desktop version is accessible via VNC or XserverSDL and comes with the desktop version of Firefox and Code OSS which is the open-source version of VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dex Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dex mode is available on Samsung phones and tablets and is pretty much the reason I chose them over another manufacturer. It allows you to turn your device into a desktop and connect an external monitor via a cable or through casting. Other manufacturers offer similar modes but Dex has been around the longest and is probably the most mature. Dex isn't essential to being able to develop on Android but it increases usability when using a mouse and keyboard however development using just the S-Pen and normal Android keyboard without Dex works brilliantly in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/dex-home.jpg" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="dex-home" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/dex-home.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things I've Tried&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this is a new "challenge" I have set myself this list is quite small but I have had no problems so far getting anything working. This whole website has been made using Code Server and the Kiwi Browser app available on Android. The website is just a simple static one created using &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; which is a static site generator written in Python. Previously the website used &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Jekyll"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and getting that set up and converted to using Pelican wasn't harder or any different to how it would be done on a PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/code-server-in-kiwi-browser.jpg" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="code-server-in-kiwi-browser" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/code-server-in-kiwi-browser.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also had success using Django, Tkinter and NodeJS. Web development seems to be a perfect candidate for using phones and tablets as development environments with even low-end devices being viable as an option. I plan to see how far I can push it regarding software development with the only issue I can foresee being any system requirements of 3rd-party libraries or dependencies not being able to be installed due to limitations with Android or because I currently haven't rooted the device.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="mobile-dev"/><category term="dev"/><category term="mobile"/><category term="termux"/></entry><entry><title>My HomeLab</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/my-homelab.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2022-12-20T18:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-20T18:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>@hreikin</name></author><id>tag:hreikin.github.io,2022-12-20:/my-homelab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A brief introduction to my HomeLab and why I have one.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;What Is A HomeLab?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn't really a set definition for the term 'HomeLab' as it means different things to different people, I'd personally describe it as something that someone could use to learn, test or tinker. I use my HomeLab for studying along with hosting different services at home. The practical experience it brings me is invaluable in my journey to becoming a System Admin as it allows me to practice the things I have learned in the safety of my environment. I am only just beginning my studying so it is currently cobbled together from various pieces of old hardware I have laying around but for me it is perfect. The &lt;a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Tech Republic"&gt;Tech Republic&lt;/a&gt; describes a HomeLab as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of a HomeLab as the technology equivalent of the scientist's laboratory. It's a place where you can experiment with new technologies, attempt to interconnect various services in novel ways and quickly clean things up when you're done. While you might be picturing a huge rack of howling servers, fortunately for us you can now create the equivalent of a small data center on a single piece of physical equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     &lt;strong&gt;&lt;cite&gt;– Tech Republic Website&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current HomeLab is very basic and quite small compared to most others I have seen online in places like &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="r/homelab"&gt;r/homelab&lt;/a&gt; but it works perfectly for what I need it to and apart from the ethernet switch it is made up entirely of hardware that was sitting around doing nothing. On top of the listed items below I also have my desktop and laptop which I use for day-to-day tasks as well as managing the services I have running over the network via SSH or the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Port TP-Link Managed Ethernet Switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x Raspberry Pi 1 Model B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x Raspberry Pi Zero 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x Odroid U3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x Intel Atom Netbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x 320 GB USB Hard Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x TFT LCD Touch Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Services Do I Host?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have quite a few different services running on my various devices and will try and outline them all now with a little description of what each one does. The 2 Raspberry Pi Model B's are running DietPi as their OS which is a Debian derivative optimized to work on SBCs. On one of them, I have running PiHole and PiVPN for network-wide adblocking and access to my network from anywhere via the PiVPN server while the other hosts ownCloud for the family to keep their photos backed up. The Odroid U3 is running Arch and is my Docker machine it runs the following containers which are mainly for monitoring my network and providing detailed stats about each machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homer Dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FreshRSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uptime Kuma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gotify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The netbook I use to host my BookStack wiki while the Raspberry Pi Zero 2 has an Apache web server running and is also my Docker test machine that I use for trying out various programs and services to see if I like them before deploying them to the Odroid U3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/home-lab-01.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-01" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-01.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/home-lab-02.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-02" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-02.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/home-lab-03.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-03" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-03.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/home-lab-04.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-04" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-04.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/home-lab-05.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-05" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-05.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/home-lab-06.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="home-lab-06" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/home-lab-06.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these little machines runs perfectly for what I have been using them for and still has room to grow without taking up much space or costing much in electricity either. Next on my wishlist is a Raspberry Pi 4B with a Cluster HAT and 4 x Raspberry Pi Zero 2's so I can practice cluster computing at home with an affordable setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about HomeLabs and Self Hosting check out these links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="r/Homelab"&gt;r/Homelab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/wiki/index" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="r/Homelab Wiki"&gt;r/Homelab Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="r/Selfhosted"&gt;r/Selfhosted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki/index" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="r/Selfhosted Wiki"&gt;r/Selfhosted Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="homelab"/><category term="open-source"/><category term="software"/><category term="self-hosting"/><category term="wiki"/></entry><entry><title>BookStack - The Self-Hosted Wiki</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/bookstack-the-self-hosted-wiki.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2022-11-28T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-28T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>@hreikin</name></author><id>tag:hreikin.github.io,2022-11-28:/bookstack-the-self-hosted-wiki.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;BookStack is an opinionated wiki system that provides a pleasant and simple out-of-the-box experience.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What Is BookStack?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BookStack is an amazing piece of Open Source wiki software and I absolutely love it, I am using BookStack at home to host information and guides I have followed for various topics along with course-related material to help with my studying. It is an easy-to-use, self-hosted platform for organising and storing information that has a very simple, yet very powerful and full-featured UI. A better description of BookStack which I have taken from the project's &lt;a href="https://github.com/BookStackApp/BookStack" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="GitHub Page"&gt;GitHub Page&lt;/a&gt; is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BookStack is an opinionated wiki system that provides a pleasant and simple out-of-the-box experience. New users to an instance should find the experience intuitive and only basic word-processing skills should be required to get involved in creating content on BookStack. The platform should provide advanced power features to those that desire it but they should not interfere with the core simple user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     &lt;strong&gt;&lt;cite&gt;– Dan Brown, Main Developer @ GitHub&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BookStack was created by Dan Brown and has an awesome set of features which make it a joy to use compared to traditional wiki software which I find can be cumbersome at times. These make the process of creating documentation enjoyable rather than boring like most of the other options I have tried. You can host BookStack locally on a PC at home or online at many hosting providers, with it being built in PHP and using MySQL to store data it has very minimal system requirements. I am currently using an old netbook with 1GB of RAM and a 1 Core/2 Thread Atom processor which handles it brilliantly, I haven't tried it yet but I think an old Raspberry Pi or similar would be a great option to run this on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Does It Look Like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BookStack has a sleek and modern interface with support for both dark and light themes, it is very refreshing and a far cry from some of the more traditional wiki software options. A &lt;a href="https://demo.bookstackapp.com/login?email=admin@example.com&amp;amp;password=password" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Live Demo"&gt;Live Demo&lt;/a&gt; is available on the website if you want to take a closer look at it and below I have included some screenshots from the official website to help give you an idea of what it is like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/bookstack-book-overview-1977x1080.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="bookstack-book-overview-1977x1080" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/bookstack-book-overview-1977x1080.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/bookstack-books-view-1977x1080.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="bookstack-books-view-1977x1080" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/bookstack-books-view-1977x1080.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/bookstack-image-manager-1977x1080.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="bookstack-image-manager-1977x1080" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/bookstack-image-manager-1977x1080.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/bookstack-page-view-1977x1080.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="bookstack-page-view-1977x1080" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/bookstack-page-view-1977x1080.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment my BookStack wiki is a little rough around the edges as it is still a work in progress so I don't have much to show and I am only hosting it locally, once I have enough content on there I will be hosting it online alongside this website. If you want to find out more information about it and start hosting your own amazing BookStack wiki then check out the project links that I have listed down below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the BookStack project check out these links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bookstackapp.com/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="BookStack Website"&gt;BookStack Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/BookStackApp/BookStack" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="GitHub Repository"&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bookstackapp.com/docs" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Official Documentation"&gt;Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://demo.bookstackapp.com/login?email=admin@example.com&amp;amp;password=password" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Live Demo"&gt;Live Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bookstackapp.com/blog" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="BookStack Blog"&gt;BookStack Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/ztkBqR2" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Discord Channel"&gt;Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bookstack_app" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="homelab"/><category term="open-source"/><category term="software"/><category term="self-hosting"/><category term="wiki"/></entry><entry><title>Simple Side Scroller</title><link href="https://hreikin.github.io/simple-side-scroller.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2022-10-27T13:57:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-27T13:57:00+01:00</updated><author><name>@hreikin</name></author><id>tag:hreikin.github.io,2022-10-27:/simple-side-scroller.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Simple Side Scroller is a 2D side scroller I am currently developing in Unreal Engine 4. I plan to release it on Android and have a web-based version for the initial release of the game with support for other platforms possibly coming later.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What Is Simple Side Scroller?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Side Scroller is a 2D side scroller I am currently developing in Unreal Engine 4. I plan to release it on Android and have a web-based version for the initial release of the game with support for other platforms possibly coming later. The initial release of the game will include 30 levels spread across 3 different game modes, "Story", "High Score" and "The Floor Is Lava" with more planned for the future. More information about UE4 can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Official Website"&gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt; and a brief description of it is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Unreal Engine, you can bring amazing real-time experiences to life using the world’s most advanced real-time 3D creation tool. From first projects to the most demanding challenges, our free and accessible resources and inspirational community empower everyone to realize their ambitions.
     &lt;strong&gt;&lt;cite&gt;– Unreal Engine Website&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial inspiration for the game came from my daughter, after seeing the insane volume of adverts in most of the games she and her brother play I decided to create my own game for them that is completely free and includes absolutely no adverts. I chose a 2D side scroller to keep the game simple for both the kids when playing it and more importantly for myself while developing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Does It Look Like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the game will be free I am trying to keep costs to an absolute minimum so all assets used within the game are open source and freely available from various great websites like &lt;a href="https://opengameart.org/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="OpenGameArt"&gt;OpenGameArt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itch.io/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Itch.io"&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt;. Thankfully there is a vast amount of great content on these sites which made my job of finding assets much easier. I have kept the look and feel of Simple Side Scroller similar to games like Super Mario with a slightly more modern approach to the assets rather than going for the traditional retro look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/simple-side-scroller-01.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="simple-side-scroller-01" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/simple-side-scroller-01.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/simple-side-scroller-02.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="simple-side-scroller-02" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/simple-side-scroller-02.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/simple-side-scroller-03.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="simple-side-scroller-03" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/simple-side-scroller-03.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/simple-side-scroller-04.png" target="_blank" title=""&gt;&lt;img alt="simple-side-scroller-04" class="image-process-article-image" src="images/derivatives/article-image/simple-side-scroller-04.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic concept for the game is similar to any other side scroller like Super Mario, the player has to complete the level within the time limit, defeating enemies and collecting coins, gems and the key required to exit the level along the way. The player can choose between different characters with different abilities to complete the game, spending the gems they collect while playing to use their abilities. Development is moving along quickly and I expect a beta release to be available soon, stay tuned for future development updates on the blog or check out the project links listed down below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Simple Side Scroller project or UE4 check out these links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/hreikin/simple-side-scroller" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="GitHub Repository"&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Unreal Engine Official Website"&gt;Unreal Engine Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.unrealengine.com/4.27/en-US/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Unreal Engine Documentation"&gt;Unreal Engine Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://opengameart.org/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="OpenGameArt"&gt;OpenGameArt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://itch.io/" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Itch.io"&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="gaming"/><category term="ue4"/><category term="gaming"/><category term="simple-side-scroller"/></entry></feed>